Saturday morning round table where we
discuss our projects and how we can best
help each other overcome the obstacles
to get them into the world I don't want
to start yeah so I could I guess I could
start with a project update so on
reasons for I'm working on a video
script just lost track of my words yeah
so I'm gonna write out the script and
then I'm probably going to want to post
it in the game be projects group for
feedback and and my canonical debate lab
group for feedback and see if before I
actually go to make it you know try and
get some human feedback and then I've
tried to reach out to some people in the
pit bull ban debate and I have not
gotten response from any people experts
on the wanting to repeal the ban but I
haven't reached out to a lot of them yet
so I got to reach out some more and then
hopefully Adriel and I will be able to
work on doing some fact-checking using
our proposed systems and see how it goes
so that's kind of the plan cool
he drove do you want to go or Shiloh
sure how many be it anymore so I had my
cousin with me last week that was a good
one went over and we started with
science did discussion part of it ended
up branching out into a few different
things and other than that I've also
been working on the specs to get the MVP
created I had a bit of a shift in the
last week where up until now I've been
sort of thinking like yeah I guess it'll
be nice if I have a prototype and then
it sort of clicked I'm like yeah it's
not optional like it's it it was I guess
kind of weird to ask for like to do to
do a Kickstarter and do stuff like that
without actually having some sort of a
prototype to be like
here's the first part of it here's what
we're actually building instead of
trying to build a community around like
the thoughts of maybe wanted to have me
an application they could do these
things so been working on this back to
actually had a good after call chat you
could get today with my couch on like
the possible software stack and stuff
like that so it's it's been good and
that's my next step is to actually get
MVP coded and online and we talked about
that a bit later might want to pick
Shiloh and I guess probably more
accurately also Billy's brain because
he's actually a developer to uh get some
feedback on software side him or not
yeah all right I can go yeah um for
solution racing in particular this week
we had two of them um Wednesday the meta
the meta conversation on like um mid
energy energy this week and I believe
yes feared energy and then we also had
on Thursday I can be mapping one with
with Mateus and James Weir as well both
of them are really really cool and next
I'm possibly the pandemic that I do in
8:30 every morning is done as of
tomorrow and then I'm gonna be
concentrating on just doing then at
least one solution rates and live online
and then whatever other ones all are
also there as well as adding the process
raising but I'm giving myself a couple
of weeks to figure figure that oaks is
gonna add two other conversations and I
realize that together in tech it's my
technology one and my Omega group is my
like spirituality the dance one so I'm
like oh I already have them I don't need
to add them in and Ed put more stuff on
my plate so right you know some stuff
over the next week including asking for
people to come and be part of that and
Raymond had suggested an expressed
interest and then I was trying to
recruit shilova so it's a fun to find a
morning that works to have a process
raising if that's something that um is
in alignment so that is what I've got
tuned what I'm gonna be up to in the
next week
hi um for my project I I've been really
busy with other stuff this week but I
did at least reach out to Raymond and
hopefully be able to talk with him about
it mostly because he's already part of
the Medicare and sea and hollow chain so
I feel like I can probably express what
I'm trying to say easier because he's
basically doing the same thing so I'm
kind of excited about that I don't know
when we'll talk but at least that's like
finally a possible connection so I'm
pretty excited and I really appreciate
you guys holding just the space you do
believe all of you just to make stuff
like that happened it's really awesome
I don't know if anyone had anything that
put them in the hot seat if anybody does
if they want to be in the hot seat and
want to do a salute you know want us to
crowdsource a solution to their issues
otherwise I guess we could have an open
conversation until something comes up um
I can start with sort of the I mean it's
fairly technical I think but we probably
don't have to dive too deep on it just
interested to hear if anyone has any
input doing some research on possible
software stacks for the wiki election
MVP so that I can actually go out and
hire a coder for it because that's a
pretty important part we don't hire a
coder is saying what you have to know in
order to actually be able to code it I
went and did some research and it seemed
like Ruby on Rails was probably where I
was headed because it seemed like it was
sort of easier to prototype and maybe
not quite as flexible and fast but four
prototypes I don't think that's terribly
you know as important and again the end
goal is you know or yes the end thing is
I'm not super attached to this being a
long term but it only lasts for a year
or two and then gets to the point where
it builds an audience and to keep kids
enough money to be able to be able to
properly from scratch that's totally
fine with me we're just interested to
hear if anyone has any input on software
stacks so my suggestion that is if
you're not tied to a software stack I
think it's okay to go out and say this
is what I want to do because like you
said there's a lot of software stacks
that would work and didn't you if not
partial then you can you can have a
broader opportunity to hire people and
then whichever one they choose you just
kind of go with because a lot of times
it really it really doesn't matter okay
my feeling on Ruby on Rails is it's more
of a it it's not
I guess for me prototypes are a little
bit easier in some sort of front-end
framework which is like angular react
overview right well Ruby on Rails is
more of a back-end thing so the main
difference is that when you click on
something or do something it goes all
the way back to the server right to the
front-end every time I guess actually
clarify
prototype probably isn't as accurate for
what I'm building it anymore it's like I
guess alpha eyeball product earlier
right like actually trying to do it so
that actually should be a back end and
it's actually going to be you know
cables and things to Lincoln and and
data to aggregate that kind of thing
yeah definitely should have a back-end I
guess
me personally I wouldn't choose any any
tech that is not a single page
application for that sorry sir yeah
single page application that's that's
that's Ruby I'm sorry that's that's
react view angular and there's quite a
few others in that space and what they
are is that it's it's mostly written in
JavaScript and most of the stuff happens
on your front end and the back end is
just an API where Ruby on Rails tends to
be like we're creating a whole
application here and it's kind of tied
to the front end because you're
generating HTML and sending it right up
to the web browser and to me I it just
seems like Ruby on Rails and anything
that's not a single page application
feels kind of old and kind of tightly
coupled so a single page application is
that like where you you would never see
the page fully reload and it's just kind
of always pulling in like Facebook now
it's mostly a single page app if you're
scrolling scrolling scrolling for seven
years and it keeps going and Facebook
yeah Facebook wrote react to be able to
do that oh and then a open source react
and that's what reason scores written in
although today I would for even quicker
prototypes I think view is the for well
curricular quicker development because
like you said you're doing over an MP
MVP
thing view is really the easiest to do
quick development in and then angular's
a good ghosting
I guess a are they easy as easy to
develop in I know a lot of the stuff
that I watched a read on Ruby on Rails
said that like its key differentiator
was that you know you could get like a
single person that knew it and you could
do in three weeks what what used to take
a small team the year to do because they
would just have to do a bunch of backend
boring crap that you can just you know
throw some some Ruby on Rails that like
look I've got like a blog that I made in
15 minutes
so it depends on when those videos are
from if they're from two years ago yes
more recently what you do is you choose
a back-end like firebase or fire store
and what that is that's a pre-built
generic API so you don't have to write
it back-end so so far in reason score I
haven't written a back-end except for
doing a little bit of security okay it's
a fully running app with multiple stuff
so if you have some sort of abstracted
back-end like fire store firebase and
there are others that yeah then you
don't have that whole thing where you
have to write a database and then you
have to write a an API layer that's all
kind of built in so if you see one of
those then then yeah angular react and
stuff but I guess that's that's true
because one thing that Ruby gives you is
the abilities you could actually just
write the code and it'll kind of build
the database in the backend and there's
a lot of technologies similar to that
that do that but I think either ways
that you could just kind of give some
examples of what you wanted you may
already have that even in your
prototypes you've done a knack and some
of the other document you have so really
just kind of can put that out there and
say get some kind of quotes and maybe
even go with the tech that most of the
people responding or saying if they'll
come in and say alright you know I do if
you get five or six react people right
now react is probably the most popular
views probably the easiest to develop in
for quicker stuff react and angular have
been built for more enterprise-e stuff
recently that's pretty simple
so you said angular and react were more
Enterprise and then view was more not
few yeah right and view is that actually
spelled viewers out just to be bue yeah
okay
I thought I thought I'd spelled it I
know it's not spelled right because it's
technology and we never spell anything
right in technology yeah right yeah I
guess reactors rectangular saying you
learn confuse for you yeah and those
will you know if you put just something
out there that's mostly what you're
gonna get and then you will get Ruby on
Rails and then you'll get some Microsoft
people doing dotnet which their
framework is very similar to Ruby on
Rails now not as faster than easy
so Ruby's not Ruby on Rails I think
would be better than the marker soft
stack okay I was going to start there
simply because every company I've worked
in has been net so it's like I mean Stu
but I don't want to talk the whole
project with that it would be a little
slower they're they're trying to bring
it into the efficiency Ruby on Rails but
I don't think they're there yet okay oh
yeah I like that so I'll just come up
with like a fairly big basic you know
probably some mock-ups in some basic
requirements post a job on top work and
see what the response comes back with
like for both the quote for how hey you
know how much effort they think it'll
take and then also what technology is if
all of the you know all the reacts come
back in its five grand and the Ruby's
come back and if $800 might be like well
right yeah and the other thing is the
suggestions I give on this which I
haven't done I haven't hurt anyone in a
while but it's to try and also get the
smallest thing so you might even say you
know make sure that they're doing
iterative development so you say I want
to you know let's just get a login
screen working or it's better you
actually start with some actual
functionality without even a login
screen so just like let's see this one
screen and show that the data persists
to the data store and back before you
move on to the neck
thing yeah I guess my concern is that on
upwork I kind of want to start with a
mini waterfall just to have the person
prove that they can do it because if you
know anybody can just make a page to
display information I could probably do
that if I did it and like yeah it came
to it but then where to go from there
well we're like okay great you built
that how long did that take you how long
was it going to take you to get to this
point and I might not arrange it that
way they'll probably still code it in
agile but like the project will probably
be like get it to two to this point and
then you'll get X dollars and then well
so waterfall is the old school of
development where you would like plan
out the whole thing like here's that how
every page is gonna work here so and
then people would sit down in code for a
year and then you would come up with an
application agile is what that would
yeah the the bits and pieces so that you
can adjust as necessary
physically no one does waterfall anymore
one of the things I like about doing it
the way Bentley suggested without
knowing the stuff you guys are talking
about is that on up works if you say you
want it on Ruby on Rails everyone's a
Ruby on Rails expert whereas if you put
out that it's this this or that then
you're gonna get people who are any of
those things and they're gonna have
projects that they did and their
favorite project might be the one that
they're they're like oh yeah I could do
in Ruby on Rails but they're good
projects are on you know the other ones
I'm so steamed are they actually which
one did they choose to do it in would
they be their best work in and theme and
it's actually a better picture of hey I
want this done what do you feel more
comfortable doing it and then also
asking them for MVP right like what do
you think is there's the waterfall what
do you think is MVP we could do it yeah
III I guess that's probably a better way
to phrase it the actual development
would still be done in agile just the
first chunk of the project is being
framed as I guess it's still not even
waterfall but like more milestone so
it's like you have to get here before
we're really considering like is this
started did you do what you said you
were going to do yeah that's determining
what that
destination is I think if someone can do
a vertical slice of a complex feature
then they can do everything else and it
also can give you a bit of a timing
concept now to your point yeah like that
login screen and that generic page is
probably not a good example it probably
good to take a complex feature that
something that differentiates your app
from the other apps and say let's do a
vertical slice of this you don't even
have to have login working you need you
might need some sort of identity
depending on the feature but here's the
one feature and right yes my national
goal was just to have like sort of a a
list of people organizations and then
there are physicians in the
organizations and sort of a really basic
way to display like here's people and
here's you know on that page show places
they've worked for just like a really
basic right here's your gear your your
database here's the the back end if you
can even call it that yet and then
here's the front end on it's just a
single page that there lists people you
can click to view them to the page hit
back go to go to a new person that kind
of thing and yeah if you if you if you
have a complex feature though I do
remember now that on a lot of projects a
lot of times it's best to hit the
riskiest piece first first of all you
kind of know whether they have the chops
to to do the whole thing and also you've
eliminated that risk before you invest
more money true I'm trying to think of
what the risk is the part of yours it
might be the voting some of the kind of
interactive voting mechanisms yeah yeah
yeah because that will end up sort of
evolving over time that's true and a lot
of it is gonna be based on how the data
ends up like that's kind of probably my
current goal is to get like thirty to
forty percent of the way there but
definitely not have the full database
and then to start like okay where can we
first bolt on some of these voting
pieces I think yeah that's probably
going to be like I'm thinking because
the content view is going to come fairly
early and I think it's first going to
come in the form of you vote on what
category legislation is and then the
sort of sister feature of now based on
how you voted on a bunch of legislation
and how
that legislation was categorized we can
now categorize your voting history
that's a dog drinking you might feed on
me yeah cuz I'd be interesting because
some of the challenges that people kind
of run into is some people don't know
how to structure a database properly so
they could store that data but they
wouldn't you wouldn't be able to have
that kind of interaction and linking it
right yeah right and that part I'm super
comfortable with designing a database
and that whole thing I mean an expert
might have some stuff to teach me on
like metadata and stuff like actual
application data I'm good there and if
you want me to do some code reviews or
stuff like that I'd be happy to if you
want to give me show me are you gonna
have all this on an open github account
or are you gonna keep it closed I'll
probably be close to start with and then
I'll figure out sort of like as a
project actually launches if and what
should be should be open cuz
imagine that some of it will end up
being open yeah so uh there's a link to
my github on my Bentley Davis comm so if
you ever want to invite me and ask me to
take a look I'm happy to i am very picky
though and i have to keep remembering
that there's multiple ways to solve a
problem so sometimes they irritate
developers because I'm like we should
have done this way and they're like oh
that's not the way I wanted it I have
that same challenge I used to work with
a developer as a product manager and
then I'd left to work in a different
department and we ended up having lunch
cuz we had like a work thing outdoors
and he even talked to me she's like you
know when your park manager I hated you
so she's like but now that you're gone I
miss you cuz like you knew what you
wanted yeah I was like that's kind of
nice so choose to focus on that yeah
that's a that's good I like starting
with the like a fairly open thing and
posting it to up work and seeing what
they come back with both for like seeing
how the cost gets tied to it and just
how many responses are for each thing
and
I mean that might even be worth to take
sort of take those stats and then to
talk about it with you or Matus or
someone and say like hey does this make
sense the interesting thing is that
motive actually knows Ruby on Rails so
that was one that I think yeah
him he's able to go and tell you know
he's done in the past and recommended
digital ocean to look into as an
alternative to Amazon to just start off
with but I mean it sounds like that's
okay they don't have the full stack
options that Amazon does so I think that
may have been based on using Ruby so if
I don't end up going that way it might
not work but I'll have to look that one
person is Ruby on Rails owned by Amazon
no no I don't think no Amazon but no um
Amazon is kind of the de facto like
hosting provider now because of their
elastic cloud and everything like
Netflix uses them a bunch of things use
Amazon that's where a big chunk of their
profit comes from now actually is that
yeah Amazon and Microsoft are the
players yeah actually Amazon does not
their major way making money is not
selling things on their website the
major way they make money is through
cloud services yeah which is interesting
that's Amazon was known for years for
Burt and for never being profitable it
was because they always spent in a
profit been building other things and
like that was one of the things they did
was they spent huge money building their
their us a cloud I think a lot of people
were like you're so stupid why are you
spending all your money well turns out
that yeah
not necessarily the place during the
roundtable but how Tesla and Amazon and
all of those operate on a deficit yes
still the people are worth billions of
dollars is really weird but that's a
whole well I mean we're seeing the
outcome of like what that risk can be
now with this where we're like the if
you operate in that way you have zero
profit zero margin like you have no
disposable cash so if you have a problem
sorry you're screwed
we've found no okay well if you operate
properly you should have some out of
money in the bank you know you should be
profitable but then those companies get
taxed and they don't do as well as a
company that pretends to not be
profitable spends all this money has no
cash in the bank and then what do we do
if we hit a wall as a society we all
have to stay inside for two months
whoops yeah I mean all of it it's like
howdy how are you the richest man in the
world and is yet its bestows the richest
now and and it's like you're being
robbed runs at a deficit it's like
because you know how could you you can't
compete with Amazon anyway even if they
are profitable right the fact they they
make it on that scale
imagine competing with them when they
have all the tax breaks they get to run
or to deficit and still be billionaires
it just makes no like it's you know make
sense under an investment standpoint and
not at all under a consumer or like
bigger game a strategy or like stability
and you know and long-term actually
having this work for a couple decades
oh yeah cuz also like if you if you're
running at a deficit anyway why not pay
your workers properly why not pay them
promote oh that's too far even the lower
rungs to have money that they can see on
that businesses that well you know going
to the economy that sounds dangerous
yeah exactly you might they might
actually think for themselves you can
feel work it's paid real money well you
guys are all in the cloud pretend II
that ones and zeros are like this fun
you billions of ones and zeros but don't
let people eat and pay their eggs have
proper health care all the money goes to
like the top 1% who don't spend
and just hoard it offshore it's working
great I know we're talking about a
vizago I was like well they can keep
their cloud then that'll be the one
thing that's profitable will be the last
thing we prior to their cold dead hands
before they go into then the third like
great until we can till and the cloud is
quite good but it's also like there are
there are definitely competitors to it
and like no reason not to compete in
that space there's a lot of people who
don't want to go with Amazon because
they're like I don't want this behemoth
like I don't want to support them their
pricing is confusing like their pricing
calculator they do so much so like I'm
fairly technical I went to go and do the
price that you'd like
I couldn't get me the pricing for
database storage to go less than three
thousand dollars and I'm like I know it
can't I don't know how to make it I told
that too much you she's like yeah I know
what you're doing the whole thing should
cost you less than twenty dollars a
month like not including coding but like
just the account and the was it the VPS
the virtual private server like oh okay
that's a lot more in line with what I
was wanting to pay to start with yeah
yeah I'm gonna even sure I'd go with the
oh yeah virtual private server yeah yeah
which I hadn't heard that acronym before
you kept saying VPS and I was it what is
it beeping yes but it made sense I was
like oh okay so it's like the server
version of a virtual machine yeah
alright that was it thank you for that
brief quite technical interlude but that
was useful and the other hot seat issues
people want to discuss it be like
writing it out and figuring out the
language and doing when I'm at like the
very beginning stages like what is a
process raising what is that's what
we're figuring out but how to explain
that in a way so that yeah I gets the
right people yeah I've I guess my only
thing is working on that video and I'm
about halfway through the script and
yeah my ideas aren't solid enough that
anyone would be able to understand it
enough to give any feedback yet I think
you want any early feedback on that I
mean I've been probably making videos
for too long I probably should have
started with the prototype but that ship
has sailed
but uh yeah if you want any feedback
there I'm happy to help
yeah I'll be definitely be posting Gabe
you know just be the script does I mean
I can make visuals and I might make some
if I get bored and want to do it because
that's the fun part
but writing out the scripts the hard
part for me okay so I'm doing and this
is for of a video so this is for a
recent score on explaining the how the
math works cuz I've got a lot of people
saying oh well that that algorithm has
to have some really powerful AI so the
people convinced I'm like no it's just
if you have one pro and one con and
they're equally important they cancel
each other out it's like you know your
six-year-old does this in their own mind
naturally it's it's nothing hard about
it but people right yeah until they see
how it works on the inside that's hard
for them to imagine that being something
simple but so yes the end result is
gonna be a video explaining that yeah
okay
one thing that might help that I've done
in the past videos is to your script but
then like put it into something like
Google slides so but you could just say
here's like a rough theorization of what
I'll be showing when I go over this part
of the text let's have a slide yeah just
so that you can sort of a show like
because I know trying to read a script
about how to explain math that's gonna
be it like just did that's gonna be
difficult to process for other oh yeah
the way I've done it right now is I'm I
have a table and split up into two
columns and one is here's what the
person is saying and then okay a written
description of kind of what's visually
happening on the screen and visually
it's pretty simple okay yeah that works
just so that there's some like some
context and I'll be talking about this
and then showing this yeah yeah cool
at first I had it written out in
paragraphs I'm like oh that doesn't work
I had that too the first time and it was
just a wall of text that was boring to
everyone else but me so I'm like alright
this is not gonna work well yeah but a
couple a couple rough draft pictures
wouldn't take that long at all to do so
that's that's a good idea
sounds like ever since I would step to
like step one is just your text of that
grid and then step two is okay in this
cell I'm showing this here's a super
rough mock-up yeah see if it makes sense
or so wouldn't take me that long to
actually do the video just cuz that's I
don't know you tend to end up fiddling a
lot when you get in there so maybe you
would
they're people the comments on a video
but to make a video depend on how much
of your time it takes in order to get
people's feedback nor you do the video
with the feedback I don't know how much
like is this you know 15 hours of work
or now we're to work and then when you
get the feedback to implement that is it
new 15 hours of work or is it just two
hours that you don't even like what yeah
this the way I'm gonna do it this time
is I'm gonna write it in JavaScript so
that I don't like record the audios in
two separate little clips and the
animation so that if I have to go in and
change a piece I can just go in and
change that piece and rerender the whole
video so that would be nice I've been
willing to do that for awhile but there
could be whole sections that I take out
because they're just distracting people
like part of its explaining of the math
but I also I found myself when I was
writing it going there and explaining
why people disagree when they both look
at the same content so that whole
section may not make it into the final
thing so I really don't want to spend
too much time building it if people go
that's a little confusing
of course I imagine most likely I'll put
the script out there and people will
either not comment or say you know I
can't picture this in my head so you'll
have to make it before you so I'm not
expecting a ton of feedback but it helps
me to work through it anyways yeah I
might be able to share some of my early
attempts of infographics with you
because I think we're trying to explain
a lot of the same things yeah yeah
did you believe are you um I know you're
still working on the process for
solution rain for you
but are you kind of thinking a bit video
introduction and process solution in our
process that sounds like a good way to
deliver your idea video is always a
great way to deliver basically any idea
it's that I don't have the ability to
make that video like I can't add the
images I can't even do a stripped in one
format so it's like my current version
until someone else can't edit and wants
to edit those you know choice or ones is
um basically keep recording so I can get
it into a 5-minute one and I yeah I
might do something like best my current
ability as I can knowing that I'm never
gonna I don't know what never but as an
individual I'm never gonna get to what I
was doing it just doesn't work for for
me I've tried tried so many times that
just going like this yep and that it's
part of like bringing people together to
have the conversation her process
raising I need to do like one little
video to explain that to bring the
people in or a comp one-off conversation
right like a conversation with my
station with you and then we're together
if we wanted more people that could be
something we create right what is this
what how do we bring people in is the
video the best place I think that you're
I don't like to use the word brand but
um kind of your image is a live type
thing so even a short just talking video
to describe your process I think it's
it's nice and helpful thank you I will
try to just i i'm not bentley both in
skill and also in like i feel like they
don't leave but don't refer it like even
bentley doing my way would come off
better like you doing Bentley's way
isn't happening it's like oh let me give
the five different reasons that this is
happening with it's like how do I
explain process Tracy we could do a
contest we could do a show we you know
what I mean and that's kind of having
other people to say here's everything we
could do what is one thing we could do
that's a process to create one and then
let's try it
endless yeah I mean agile this seems to
like a great candidate process for you
know how do you make videos what tools
do you use or how does the script of
building work
[Music]
there's a lot that goes into making
videos writing it like from is this a
video like this is it and you know
infographic style explainer yeah I think
a lot of times just a person speaking
passionately is very powerful yeah I
mean the only reason I'm getting
valuable and is so the stuff is that I
am trying to explain something very
technical but I think that that wouldn't
be that I think I think Jubilee you have
a great skill set for what you're trying
to do so I look forward to seeing it and
someone coming alongside later on and
just doing it a little editing might
help but yeah well the other thing that
is nice is you just doing these videos
and talking about multiple times even if
you just record where you've talked
about it in a month you just go wash all
those bits and pieces and the
surrounding conversations and be like oh
I like that part I like that part I like
that part
oh crap a script that yeah I have
writing a script I just there's times
where I just cut like I didn't go live
but I just sort of start talking and do
the conversation and record myself on
video and then go back later and watch
it and I say things that I'm like oh I
couldn't have written that out of my
mouth to be like alright that's out
there now I guess that works yeah that
happens all the time and it happens more
often when like I'm talking to mom on
skype and it recorded in anyway and it's
like why this moment can I explain this
it's generally also like when I am
frustrated sometimes and I'm trying like
it's like all the gobbledygook and then
the actual thing like then this three
minutes of like this beautifully aligned
heart and brain speaking like yes just
cut that section out except we didn't
record it and I'm talking to my mom but
you know just call the NSA see if they
have a copy or the Canadian equivalent
know the NSA probably has it okay it's
on Google devices yeah no come on I just
you recording
saying this thing that's going to take
you down in a few but which is is part
of this whole thing is how many people
have amazing ideas and projects that
aren't it's beyond that cultural being
on camera because I get that one that is
but like the how many people I know who
are like I'm here to save the planet but
also don't look at my name don't look at
my face don't because someone could come
kill me and I'm like those things can't
be in a lot like you need to put
yourself out there enough so that it's
safe enough for all it like it's it's
hard enough with me putting myself out
here constantly and I've had to get
through the layers of that like I'm
still in caves my kid being on camera
you bring me I don't show where I live
and there's certain things that I'm
definitely to keep it safe but like I'm
on camera and it's hard I can't imagine
being like no no not not my face not my
name and then how does my idea get out
there with you and your face and your
name yeah well and if your idea is any
kind of world-changing idea Trust is
such an important factor and like who
are they trusting in that case like a
voice on a screen yeah that can't be
gamed at all we live in that we are so
getting close to the world thank God for
Bentley and Adriel because like this
stuff is coming out coab in 90 it just
all of it right it's like how dare your
stupid to believe that I'm like you know
any documentary can be done nowadays and
exactly what you're saying about the
other side can be said about your side
and we're getting in such a sense of
like senselessness that everything can
be doctored and you can't trust anything
but we have to figure out trust in a
higher level so she beautiful big I
don't know because it was in my kid's
textbook doesn't mean it's true
even though it was printed but yours how
do we know well that's I mean and I
think that's really been a big shift in
the last 10 to 20 years we're prior to
that look I think we still mostly
trusted experts we knew we couldn't
really trust governments or media but
we're like at least the experts do it
and now we're like oh that's gone too
well I mean it's video and my voice is
gone right like it seemed
someone say something right like as much
as I don't like Trump and he says enough
asinine things he doesn't like you could
get a Trump to say basically anything
and so if I see him saying something
ridiculous I'm going to assume it's true
it might not be right it might be a bot
it might be anything and it's like so
what do we trust I trust 7 people
recording the same Trump at a rally if I
can have access to that but not you know
and even then they could be different
like I need some other people to also
know that's going on so they cannot wait
I'm here too and that's not happening
I'll start recording right see in those
cases when they disagreed the technology
to spot deep fakes and audio editing and
all that sort of thing so that it's yeah
a single part where you're like if it's
here it's as close as we can reasonably
be to being sure it's true yeah I've
been thinking a lot several of my
friends on Facebook have been basically
saying you shouldn't trust anybody
especially in an official capacity and
their goal seems to be to sow distrust
and it's been triggering me but I'm not
sure if that's a good response for me
because realistically it is good to have
to be suspect and to think through so
I'm working through why am I so
frustrated when I see someone kind of
doubt you know well so my friends just
blatantly aren't wearing masks and stuff
like that and and they seem to think
it's conspiracy which no doubt a lot of
the information is wrong but it seems to
me that their emotional goal is to sow
distrust between people but I don't
think that's accurate I think that's my
emotional reaction to what I think it's
partially true but I think it's they're
trying to prove their own distrust is
they're starting from a place that I
don't trust and others say here's why
you should
either I I haven't trusted these em
efforts for glass you know twenty years
here's why I'm right it's a really
interesting time to be here right now
the government's have not done a great
job in countering those people like
they've they've been inept and corrupt
and like using this as blatantly up
times are like in Canada changing the
gun laws and all this for like I can
kind of see why but also maybe enforce
the gun laws we have like there's a
bunch of stuff like and you can see
across all countries like all the states
they're not doing a great job at trying
to say hey we're not using this as
excuse to further government overreach
they're definitely doing that but now
the question is is there also a reason
for them to do of course but then how
was the average person supposed to tell
the difference and that's where it's
like the average people need to get
together and create that difference so
that because that is like I'm mainly
talking about this documentary called
the plan debbik that came out which if
you watch it is somewhat convincing and
if you are against it you can absolutely
find flaws in it and it's like the
documentary itself is not and then of
course the young the Michael Moore
documentary is well they came out with
food you know that discounting the green
New Deal basically in the green industry
and and then the environmental is like
this is the best we have stopped
discounting it like this whole people
yell at each other for being stupid and
you're too naive and you're trusting but
there's no way to assess that and like
so the we're really like the actual
solution is we all do our own individual
research and then get together and fight
about it is that what we're doing like
that doesn't help because we can fight
all day about whether we should wear
masks if you're not wearing one that's
putting me at risk you know like this is
there's the actual action that we want
people to take ie wearing masks or stay
inside social distancing and then if
they're not that like they're wrong
because they didn't come to the same
conclusion I did they're basing it on
the wrong facts it's like well how do I
know my facts are right I we need to
take and like they don't trust the
government's they're overreaching I
totally am in alignment and please wear
a friggin ass like and that's very like
it's interesting time to be alive
because those of us who knew not to
trust the government in the media are
actually the people
simultaneously except yes like how do we
hold them not respond like how do we let
them not have the overreaching fascism
that's coming about and to collectively
listen to our best advice that's out
there and it's by like building that
trust and information system that we
require that doesn't cuz you get the
government created one we're not gonna
trust it because the media created one
we're not gonna trust it yeah like I do
laugh as the things on Facebook we're
now they're starting to do fact-checking
you know like no one is gonna trust
Facebook to do that zero real people and
yeah everything I've been seeing is just
that people being like all Facebook is
trying to censor us yeah I kind of
figured that without how this will kind
of feeds into their concerns yeah it's
not the net result isn't always positive
and it seems like you know whenever we
do our own research if we're doing it
off of any of our own devices the
algorithms are really based on our own
likes and dislikes very true yeah yeah
so you're doing research in this
pre-selected like okay there's lots of
gold in these hills cuz I just got this
one sample that was half gold that
somebody curated for me and now it's
yeah that's not actually what's out
there it's also hunters even if you do
the research there's tools working
against you to maybe limit the pool of
research that you you're that you'll be
presented that way yeah and that
frustrates me when people say oh you
need to do the research on these
questions why is this happening why is
this happen I know that that doesn't
work I'm going to come to different
conclusions than you and I don't even
know what conclusions you're getting at
all's I know is that you were hoping
that other people will be drawn to
conspiracy to your conspiracy because
they'll Google and they'll happen to get
the same results or they'll do an
internet search and that points gonna
come don't say do me the research tell
me what you believe and tell me why
yeah well point me to the research you
used right like even there did you
actually do research because 98% of the
people that say that they didn't do the
research either they read an article
from somebody who knew somebody who you
know had a brother-in-law who
like someone else you know had once
walked by somebody who read the research
yeah yeah and realistically though I
haven't done full research and they
can't share their opinions flat-out
because they will get because people be
attacked by people are you one of those
people attacking them if somebody says
here's the research I followed then
they're being too open and now they open
themselves up it's your - if somewhat
yeah if someone doesn't believe that
vaccines are safe like probably my
father he posted something from this
book saying that you know from the 1920s
saying how vaccines are dangerous and
stuff and I said well I actually did an
interview with him and stuff but no time
would he say he I says he says I just
think people need to look at it and I'm
like you're chicken yeah but rightfully
so it was rational for him to not put
all this it's too dangerous to put all
of your information on the table which
is unfortunate but I find it very
frustrating because I can't I can't he
and I cannot reach a an understanding
because everything has to be a lot of
the information has to be kept secret
hopefully had realized tools will help
with that but I'm frustrated by recently
very helpful is having tools to do those
kind of kind of things because no we're
never gonna be able to tackle a subject
without emotions involved and to be able
to see what does somewhat unbiased
science say and then make that science
as unbiased as possible knowing who
funded it you know why all this research
what research is missing because that is
a big piece for it for me
as someone who has looked into the
vaccines and thought I would back to say
my kid and it didn't because all the
missing research that the doctors could
I was like right there's no research
showing it's not safe
you also have done no research for ten
or twenty thirty years like on the
long-term effects of it that's big huge
missing science and there's things that
show the dogs and cats and horses and
pigs are negative
affected by them but none for humans and
it's like oh mannequin things work shows
out of November what vaccine it was that
gives you acne and they took it out and
I was like I think I'd rather have acne
the measles but at the same time it's
like they were like well that shows it
in a bad light so we have to retract it
it's like that's bad science really bad
science no it's from UBC right I think
so yeah I think that was the one I read
it a story that I couldn't find again in
the future
that was the publisher study and it was
like the most innocuous thing you know
something like it causes acne the most
like who cares oh yeah they were asked
to unpublish it and I was like that
doesn't sound right yeah which is but
having like the point yeah one of the
challenges so many people are having to
play mental games just like in voting
and politics and stuff like sometimes
you don't vote for the person you want
to win because that boat will cost
someone else because we do
first-past-the-post same thing and
information-sharing is that you know
sigh you know like they the government
came out and said you shouldn't wear a
mask because it doesn't protect you and
then six months later they reversed well
it's because when they did that first
statement or at least I think I could be
wrong that they were trying to convince
people to do something so they
exaggerated the situation right if
they'd just been honest and said there's
not enough stuff in the United States
right now for all the for all of our
medical care people so even though it
would help slow down the spread to wear
a mask we're gonna ask you to stay home
instead and leave that equipment for
them and here's their logic why but also
if they'd tried that message it probably
wouldn't have hit because they don't
they don't we don't have a communication
tool that can get that level of clarity
out so they're in a tough situation
where they kind of have to be
manipulative and it comes and bites them
in the butt yeah that is that exact has
being transparent if they had done that
you know what then happens there's a run
on all the masks like oh they're like
because it's like right people who are
like okay it's more important for the
nurses
help them I'm not gonna have them then
you don't mean but other people are like
wait no there's it's a natural response
it's a collective it's a collective
action issue that to also because each
individual it is the right decision for
us to go and buy a mask that is the
correct decision selfishly for us but
now we as a group how can we as a group
say okay we're all going to take a risk
to have a greater potential for all of
us later but the risk only lowers if
everyone does it but if any group small
group people doesn't do it it's better
for all of us to not do it and that's
that collective action they show you
that mask is super weird because it
doesn't protect you it protects us
everybody else so like Trump and pensive
like why we don't have it I'm like yeah
you're getting tested every day so you
can keep your masculinity and not wear a
freaking mask while telling everyone
else to wear a mask put on a freaking
mask it's not because if you were like
oh just let everyone else go about their
business and the people who are
susceptible people who this is a higher
risk or can wear a mask and gloves but
the math the mask isn't to protect you
it's to protect everybody else if you
have it it does not protect you from
viruses in the airport X's viruses from
going in the air I mean in the end it it
protects you a little bit because you're
if you have relatives that if you have
friends they're not dying
and then also society wise you know
there's there's knock-on effects but
yeah there it's kind of there's
long-term benefits and short-term
benefits in the short term yeah but
meaning that like actually what's best
for me is everybody in society to wear a
mask and Mina gonna give up my last one
right if I'm looking out for me because
you guys are gonna affect me and at the
same time I want a horde vote right like
it's like I want it like it's so
counterproductive and at the same time
it's like right just use anything it
doesn't need to be sterile it doesn't
need to be it's just about blocking it a
little bit and then all the people who
are like constantly on like this and
then they'll let it me down here you
know like that's not I'll be out here I
went down to talk
I went to Costco it was so bad like 1/4
the people have it like this and yeah
and and then all the workers had them
and they kept having to go like this to
talk and like what the why even have
them right yeah yeah it's just longer at
that point yeah yeah I was doing I was
going through a drive-thru and they they
have people I guess to get the cars
through faster they have workers
standing out there and one of them had
it here that first of all let's not have
the workers there we can take a little
time extra time sitting in our car and
going up and talking through the machine
rather than talking to a person you know
a foot from my car I just I don't I
don't understand I would rather sit in
my car longer and be sterile yeah the
other interesting thing about that
conversation around the government you
know sort of like kind of innocently
enough being like hey don't wear masks
to try and do it it made sense but they
were also covering up their own
incompetence because they shouldn't even
had to do that there should be a
civilian supply and a stockpile and
everyone knew this or these all
governments knew this and nobody had it
well we had a stockpile in the US and we
shut it down a couple years ago yeah
exactly
and then now is there as apparently for
the federal workers and not the states
and I mean everyone has their different
way of interpreting it based on what
they want and I also find like we're in
a pen a very specific condemning right
it's respiratory virus that you stay
pissed six to eight feet of paper apart
from people and it's like everyone's
yelling at the government like you
didn't plan for this and you're like
right because you don't have any misses
there are like truly there's every kind
of pandemic there's every kind of
natural disaster there's terrorists
there's it's like everything so yeah
what we actually need is people who care
about the terror that everything to be
thought like you give thought experiment
what are we doing this and what are we
doing this now we're bringing those
people for to belike who you knew this
was gonna happen before it happened so
you must like it's like no you just pick
the people who are the right Horsemen of
the Apocalypse right they they kicked
the rice first REM that was gonna happen
they didn't necessarily know that other
people were like we knew something was
happening yeah like I mean people need
to know that our governments can handle
any any catastrophe they can't the issue
is we need to know what every
catastrophe is and then what the
and we needs a planet top-down yeah then
they're like Oh fiscally like this is
bringing our fiscal and our healthcare
together right like all of the things we
couldn't do for decades four people are
now going by the wayside right leg even
people fighting for ubi and stuff but
thinking about like classroom sizes you
know long teachers have been fighting to
bring down their classroom sizes and now
all the sudden they're like well yeah
well what would six feet apart so if we
want kids back in here and we need this
so we're gonna need more teachers we're
gonna need more classroom we're gonna
need now there's money for you wait how
how is that possible now all of a sudden
everyone's doing remote learning where
as I like in my job working for the
government I couldn't do it from home
which is one of the reasons I wasn't
able to do it everyone I used to work
with is not working from home and it's
like yeah cuz now all this sudden it's
okay to have the social insurance number
at your house right cuz it wasn't and I
get it it made sense both ways and yet
now we're seeing all this stuff and so
now if I went back and was like hey I
can work from home I think they have
less of a reason to say no because we
did it during the pandemic but like it's
all these fiscal policies coming up
against our healthcare ones and like now
we're like yeah how long-term you need
to plan for risk yeah well I think also
an important thing that I think it's
lost in the whole conversation because
much is I'm not a fan of really any
government the conversation that have
heard for all governments it's like oh
you were warned and did nothing do you
think I never hear all that is okay but
how many warnings do they get and how
are they waited are they told 7,000
things a day here's the 7,000 things
that could go wrong and and one thing on
on January 17th that one item that's
what ended up happening or was it they
were told time and time and time again
this was the only thing that was really
being brought up those are two very
different scenarios where I don't think
we're told about this in December and
January right what all could have put
stock in respiratory stuff we all could
have been stock like but they're the
government they're the authority and
they better like it's right how many
things do they need to plan for and then
what is plan for and so I want to give
and we're coming up to the hour when you
give Shilo a chance to say something
snarky I'm you didn't muted I mean it's
a little off-topic but not really I was
just wondering about your guys's
projects and
if you see a time line is there like
could you have your projects finished in
a year let's say what do you guys I mean
in my case the project will never be
done because it's a bite against
misinformation right so if I build
something to people who want this
information to come out there they'll
adjust and do something else we'll have
to go over that so it's going to be like
sort of a continual battle but I think
yeah in under a year
you know if development starts now and
you know there's a decent pickup in
audience I think it could you know be a
fairly strong tool in here and mine is
kind of in private data right now with
one person and so I'm going to grow that
and I hope to be like having like
sharing the content more widely in the
future over the next month or so
and then I only have a year's runway so
something's gonna happen either either
I'm gonna find funding or I'm gonna get
a real job but yeah so I hope to find
some funding in the next six months and
then have people start using it I don't
know the the future vision of the tool
where people can actually just kind of
go in and add their feedback and it
would be a real community system maybe a
while because the moderation tools will
take quite a bit of work and and I just
don't have the justification for that
yet but something usable and launched to
the public in the next several months
hopefully not in time not enough to
affect the upcoming election in the
United States which I have a I have a
friend who's built a similar tool and he
is really pushing for us to have a
material effect on the election in the
US I am doubtful it's pretty soon yeah
my my timeline is is both I mean anytime
you get once we have 10,000 people then
every project gonna take six months to
make it and we start one every six
months everything can snowball very
rapidly and and it's already happening
now right Barbie doing solution raisins
already
people together for projects already
doing so like it's happening and at any
point we get a threshold of people
involved it can happen even more rapidly
and once you have the ten thousand
people in the process it's about
figuring out that process and tweaking
it will never be done but having the
first iteration of an agile process we
already have it like solution raising is
it and then getting people together to
do the process so how about you Shiloh
what do you see for a timeline for years
I suppose I feel like if I did connect
with someone like Raymond who would look
at my design I guess and I guess I need
to talk with them but I would think I
could probably do it within a year and I
only asked because I mean ideally I'd
love to have our exhibition where I was
able to help people introduce these
types of things and so I'm trying to
give myself probably a year or less as
well goal to establish that and in my
end it's a little bit different because
I have to then find venues to apply for
and I'm also I'll have to probably apply
for grant money that kind of thing
through different art associations so
it's kind of a lot of that kind of work
but I do feel like I could probably have
enough art for a show with an ear for
sure I have so that's just the thought
you guys are ready maybe I'll be able
that carried right you right we're at
the hour should we say goodbye to
YouTube and end it for this week and I
will post out all the videos this time
for Sunday yeah and then send those send
those as well was the one Facebook
groups sounds good
all right I Yujin